JACK: Torchwood.
Outside the government,
beyond the police.
Fighting for the future
on behalf of the human race.
The 2 1 st century
is when everything changes
and Torchwood is ready.
Gwen, texting you the location.
Appearing four or five signs of life.
Definitely non-human.
-Get here as soon as you can.
-So, sure they're not Weevils?
Don't think so.
Different energy patterns.
Can't make sense of it.
-Not a species we've encountered before.
-Let's hope they're friendly, then.
Owen, Ianto, take the other side
of the building. Check the upper floors.
Toshiko, with me.
Okay?
Go.
I'm getting mirror readings
on both floors.
One creature at either end
of the building.
Toshiko, split up.
You know,
these creatures are very quiet.
Maybe they're sleeping.
Or hatching.
Or maybe they aren't creatures at all.
Just explosive devices.
Snap.
(RINGING)
Shit!
-You have one message.
-IANTO: Gwen, texting you the location.
-Appearing four or five signs of life.
-Shit!
(GASPING)
Not again.
(GRU NTING)
Ladies!
Torso of steel, shilling a feel.
Any takers?
(GRU NTING)
Bar fight, got a little out of control.
Flesh wound.
Oh ! Still not used to...
These hangovers.
Captain Jack Harkness.
How long have you been there?
Silent types? That's okay.
I used to date a guy with no mouth.
Surprisingly creative.
Now listen, you only had to ask.
Can we get a room, though?
(COUGHING)
(SCREAMING)
When I said about getting a room,
I meant somewhere with linen.
(SCREAMING)
Time was electrodes to the nipples
meant the start of a good night.
(JACK SCREAMING)
(JACK LAUGHING)
Full power charge and still breathing.
Pretty advanced piece of equipment
you got there.
You ladies are ahead of yourselves.
Now where the hell am I?
Put that down before someone gets...
(GASPING)
Why aren't you dead yet?
-Been trying to figure that out myself.
-We've been monitoring you.
You've been killed 14 times
in the last 6 months.
-Feels like more than that.
-Who's the Doctor?
No idea.
"The Doctor. He will be able to fix me."
"When the Doctor turns up,
it'll all be put right."
"You wait till I see the Doctor."
" First I'm going to kiss him,
then I'm going to kill him."
-Why do you want to know?
-You're in Torchwood, Cardiff.
The Torchwood Institute was created
to combat the threat posed by the Doctor
and other phantasmagoria.
JACK: He's not a threat!
The Doctor is the one who will save you
from your phantasma-hoogits.
-Just tell us his location.
-I don't know!
He left me behind.
I came here to find him.
He refuels from that rift you have.
Hoping if I stayed here long enough,
we'd find each other.
Now...
-Can I go?
-No.
-You can't keep me here.
-We can.
-Unless.
-Yes. Unless...
Unless what?
There are opportunities here
with the Institute.
-I'm not for hire.
-You're going to need currency.
-What's the assignment?
-Missing person.
Well, when we say person...
I haven't done anything.
12 burglaries,
joyriding a horse and carriage,
seven cases of pickpocketing,
24 instances of consuming food
without paying for it.
It's like an addiction
with your species, isn't it?
I'll make it up, I promise.
-Ohh. Too late.
-It's just a bit of fun.
This planet's a century away from
official first contact with alien life.
-You're upsetting the schedule.
-Who are you?
I'm Torchwood.
I said sorry! You can't lock me up.
He's just a kid.
Send him back to where he came from.
If only we could.
The rift only goes one way.
What do you do?
Observe and profile the species,
then transfer them to long-term storage?
-Why!
-He was a threat to the Empire.
-Like me?
-You're our ally now.
If you don't want it...
-Your next assignment.
- (SCOFFS) No.
-I'm through with you people.
-Your liberty is at our discretion.
Work for us, you assist the Empire.
Sever that tie, you become a threat.
And you've seen
how we deal with threats.
It's good money, Captain.
How else are you going to earn?
(JACK SIGHING)
See what you think in the morning.
He's pretty. But you're prettier.
Can I read your cards?
No, thank you.
No, really.
He's coming, the one you're looking for.
The century will turn twice
before you find each other.
Ooh. Are you for real?
You mean I have to wait
a hundred years to find him?
(SCOFFS)
What'll I do in the meantime?
REPORTER: ...some parts of the world
have already welcomed in the new year.
And our cameras,
of course, have been out in force
across the U K tonight.
Let's take you first to Cardiff.
Hey! When you joked about
the millennium bug,
I didn't realise it was going
to have 18 legs stacked with poison.
Anyone home?
Hey, you know you're supposed to
party like it's...
Alex.
Jack. Just in time.
Alex?
-What happened? Who did this?
-Me.
What?
Why?
We got it wrong, Jack.
We thought we could control
the stuff we found.
And what's it brought us? So much death.
-What happened to them?
-It's good you're here.
Always did have great timing.
This place, it's yours.
Torchwood Three.
My gift to you, Jack, for a
century of service as field operative.
Fill this place with purpose.
Before it's too late. Please.
Alex, listen.
-It's going to be okay.
-No.
It's not.
It's really not.
I looked inside.
It showed me what's coming.
They were mercy killings.
It's the kindest thing I could do.
So none of us see the storm.
(CH EERING ON TV)
I'm sorry I can't do the same for you.
2 1 st century, Jack.
Everything's going to change.
(CH EERING ON TV)
-And we're not ready.
-Alex!
(GU NSHOT)
(GASPING)
(JACK SCREAMING)
He was dead !
I checked his pulse. He was dead !
All right. Shh !
Jack, what's happened?
Where are the others?
-What is he doing here?
-I was late. He give me a lift.
-You okay?
-Yeah. Yeah.
Toshiko, she went the other way.
(JACK SHOUTING IN TH E DISTANCE)
GWEN : Toshiko, yell if you can hear me!
JACK: Toshiko! Toshiko!
(PANTING)
(SCREAMING)
(KEYBOARD CLICKING)
Never thought I'd say this
to anyone here,
but you work too hard.
Another hour and I'm done.
I wish the rest of them
thought like you.
At 5: 30, they're out of here
like a pack of dogs.
-You have a good evening, sir.
-I doubt it.
Another late one, Miss Sato?
You know me, George, married to the job.
When are you going to let me
whisk you away from all this?
As soon as you clear it
with your wife and grandchildren.
-Always an excuse. Take care.
-Good night, George.
-I've got it.
-Get in.
(BEEPING)
I want to see my mother.
I want to know she's safe.
Now.
Show me the piece.
It's beautiful.
A perfect sonic modulator.
-Toshiko, you've done so well.
-Toshiko!
(SPEAKING JAPAN ESE)
You've got what you want.
Now let her go.
Well, except now,
you're the victim of your own success.
Perfectly situated, proven ability.
You can give us so much more.
(SPEAKING JAPAN ESE)
-And what if I refuse?
-Then your mother stays with us.
And your brilliance is used against her.
-Like this.
-No. Don't...
(SCREAMING)
SOLDIER 1: Turn it off! Turn it off!
SOLDIER 2 : Get down !
TOSHIKO: My mother!
Is she all right? Is she all right?
WOMAN ON SPEAKER:
This is a UNIT facility.
Your rights as a citizen
have been withdrawn.
You'll be held here indefinitely.
We are not required to provide you
with legal representation.
Anything you say will be recorded.
You will be allowed no communication
with any person or organisation
outside this facility.
There is no right of appeal.
If you fail to comply with the rules,
we are authorised to discipline you.
Is my mother safe?
We cannot supply you
with that information.
Prisoner Sato, inspection.
What for?
Prepare for inspection.
(DOOR U N LOCKING)
JACK: Catering's as lousy
as they say, huh?
-TOSHIKO: Where's my mother?
-She's safe.
She won't remember being kidnapped.
I wiped it from her memory.
-I hope you don't mind.
-You did what?
Really just a little pill.
She'll never have known.
-Who are you?
-Nobody.
I don't exist.
And for a man with my charisma,
that's quite an achievement.
-Are you a lawyer?
-Do I look like a lawyer?
They're going to make an example of you.
Stealing official secrets
in today's climate,
they're going to keep you here
without charge.
-Forever.
-They can't do...
They're never going to release you.
I'm sorry.
You made this, right?
-I just followed the plans.
-Yeah, kinda.
But first, you had to grasp the concept
of what a sonic modulator does.
Most people would struggle with that.
And another thing,
-the plans don't work.
-What?
The technical plans you followed,
they were wrong.
They had mistakes in them.
That's why the plans were shelved.
But you, Toshiko Sato,
you automatically fixed things
as you went along.
What I'm trying to say is,
oh, baby you're good.
I mean, you're good now,
imagine what you'd be like
with a little training.
Shame you're going to be locked up
for so long.
-You've got to get me out of here.
-If you
-come work for me.
-Really?
Give me five years,
I'll get them to wipe your record clean.
They owe me a few favours.
-What do you do?
-Protect people.
At least that's what I'm aiming for.
It's kind of a work in progress.
-What about my mother?
-Limited contact only,
you can send her postcards.
So what do you say?
-Why would you trust me?
-Instinct.
It's going to be dangerous.
Think you could bear a little danger?
(SCREAMING)
GWEN : Stop, stop, stop! Stop!
-Tosh, Tosh, you okay?
-You're making it worse.
It's pushing down even more.
I think I've broken my arm.
-Gwen...
-Yeah?
If this pillar shifts down even more,
it will crush me.
It's no good, Gwen. We're going to need
more strength...
Okay, look, Jack has gone
to find Owen and Ianto.
You're going to be fine, darling,
all right? You're going to be fine.
You've got to hurry, please.
-Gwen, help Jack. I'll stay here.
-Are you sure?
-Yeah.
-I'm going to come back for you.
-You're going to be okay.
-TOSHIKO: Okay.
Gwen, this could've been you,
couldn't it? If you hadn't been late.
Rhys, I haven't got time
for this now, okay?
I've got to go
and try and find the others.
(SCREAMING)
JACK: Ianto! Ianto!
(GROWLING)
(JACK SCREAMING)
(IANTO GRU NTING)
-Thanks.
-No. Thank you.
-And you are?
-Jones.
-Ianto Jones.
-N ice to meet you, Jones, Ianto Jones.
Captain Jack Harkness.
-Lucky escape.
-I had it under control.
You think so? Looked pretty vicious.
You're, um...
-You were bleeding.
-Had worse from shaving.
Looked like a Weevil to me.
I have no idea
what you're talking about.
I'll take him from here.
-Thanks for the assistance.
-Any time.
By the way, love the coat.
Morning.
Coffee?
Wow.
-I wanna work for you.
-Sorry. No vacancies.
-Look, let me tell you about myself.
-Ianto Jones.
Born August 19th, 1983.
Able student, but not exceptional.
One minor conviction for shoplifting
in your teens.
N umber of temporary jobs,
mainly a drifter,
until two years ago, you joined
the Torchwood Institute in London.
Junior researcher.
Girlfriend, Lisa Hallett.
-Deceased.
-Sorry.
-Look, you checked me out.
-You knew what a Weevil was.
Thought I was going to have to come
"deal with you".
But instead, you can see I have
the right qualifications for the job.
There is no job. We're nothing to do
with Torchwood London.
I severed all links.
Yet when it burnt, two members
of your team scavenged the ruins.
I don't want the equipment
getting into the wrong hands.
And you're the right hands, are you?
-Trial period. Three months.
-No.
Three weeks. Three days.
Let me prove myself to you.
I'll work for nothing.
No.
I saw what they did at Canary Wharf.
What am I supposed to do
with those memories?
You are not my responsibility
and we're not hiring.
Same time tomorrow, then.
There is no job for you here
and there never will be.
I really like that coat.
JACK ON RADIO: Toshiko, see if you can
decode those hieroglyphics.
TOSHIKO: Already on it.
JACK: Owen, take a cross-section
of the paramedic's brain.
Check it against
the list of chemical agents.
OWEN : Will do.
JACK: Suzie, we're going to need
to dredge the reservoir.
See if you can find the other half...
Oh.
-Okay, this has to stop.
-No. Listen to me.
I don't have time for this.
Look, I don't care what your problem is.
I want you out of this city by sunrise.
There is no place for you here.
Go back to London,
find yourself another life.
Keep stalking me, I'll wipe your memory.
-No, but the thing is...
-Look, any conversation between us,
no matter what the subject, is over.
Finished. Done. Forever.
I'm getting back
behind the wheel of that car,
if you're still standing in the road,
I'm gonna drive through you.
So you're not going to help me
catch this pterodactyl, then?
Okay, that is the only
special equipment you've got?
Yeah. 'Cause I keep dinosaur nuts
in the back of the SUV.
Torchwood London would've...
(PTERODACTYL SQUAWKING)
Nope.
-How did you find it?
-Rift Activity Locator.
-Torchwood London.
-See, quality kit.
-Yeah, it's quite excitable.
-Must be the aftershave.
-Never wear any.
-You smell like that naturally?
5 1 st century pheromones.
People have no idea.
-Ready for another go?
-I'm game if you are.
Three, two, one.
(PTERODACTYL SQUAWKING)
Shh. Shh. Shh.
(JACK CH UCKLING)
We're not going to harm you.
You can't stay here.
Come back with me.
I've got somewhere nice and big
where you can fly around.
Okay, so you let the pterodactyl in
but not me?
-I need a guard dog.
-I could be that.
A receptionist? Building maintenance?
Food and drink?
Dry cleaning even? That coat of yours
must take a battering.
-Like a butler, I could be a butler.
-We don't need a butler.
Excuse me. Dried egg on your collar.
-It was a busy week.
-What exactly is your plan?
-I'm gonna be the decoy.
-And it won't rip you to shreds?
Dinosaurs? Had them for breakfast.
Had to.
Only source of food protein
after the asteroid crashed.
Long story. Here you go.
One injection to
the central nervous cortex.
I'll keep it occupied. Move.
-No.
-What?
It knows me. I'll be a better decoy.
-Way too dangerous.
-No, I've got a secret weapon.
Chocolate. Preferably dark.
(WHISTLING)
Got your favourite. Yeah.
(PTERODACTYL SCREECHING)
It's good for your serotonin levels,
if you've got serotonin levels.
Whoa !
Whoa ! Ianto!
(JACK GRU NTING)
Sorry.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
I should go.
Hey!
Report for work first thing tomorrow.
Like the suit by the way.
(JACK GRU NTING)
JACK: Ready? Three.
One, two, three. Come on.
Oh, my God. Come on. Come on, come on.
(IANTO SCREAMING)
-You okay?
-My shoulder. I think it's dislocated.
-Can you take this?
-Yeah.
Take a deep breath.
-Where are the others?
-We need your help to get Toshiko out.
-Owen?
-No sign yet.
If anything happens,
he can't repair himself.
-Of course, he can't heal, can he?
-Okay, we'll help Rhys with Toshiko.
Let us know when you find Owen,
and be careful.
Okay.
Okay? You all right?
(CREAKING)
Oh, go on.
Please, please, please, please.
No. You don't even like her,
ever since she didn't pay for her share
of the Chinese in Leicester.
Yeah, but we want Julia to come
and it'd look odd
if we invite one without the other.
Oh, God, help me please. Help me, God.
Three tables done. N ine more to go.
You wanna back out?
It's still not too late.
Listen, I'm marrying you
even if it kills me, okay?
H mm.
Good.
You want a cup of tea?
-Yeah, I'll make one.
-Think I can manage.
-Katie?
-Yeah?
Erm...
Water.
Yeah.
From the kettle.
(KATIE SIGHING)
Milk.
Stop nagging me.
I don't want to have milk.
I've never liked milk. I want to have...
-Tea.
-I wanna have tea without...
(SIGHING)
-Milk.
-Tea without milk.
(BANGING)
(KATIE CRYING)
It's all right. It's all right.
MAN : I got your invitation.
It's still going ahead?
-I promised her a summer wedding.
-Before all this.
-This changes nothing.
-Owen, it will change everything.
-You don't know for certain.
-We've been through Kate's test results
more times than any patient
in my whole career.
You've looked through them yourself.
All the evidence suggests
she has early onset Alzheimer's.
-The youngest case in medical history.
-Doesn't mean we're wrong.
OWEN : Please.
Run more tests.
Let's just try one more MRI scan.
-An MRI isn't gonna make any difference.
-You don't know that now.
You have said yourself that this
is unlike any case that you've seen.
-Maybe you've missed something.
-Owen.
You don't understand, Jim, okay?
One day she's fine,
she has perfect memory, the old Katie,
and the next, there's nothing.
She's blank.
Now I am losing her
and I don't know
what to do about that, okay?
So please...
What's the point of me doing this job
if I can't help my own fiancée?
-I'll see what I can do.
-Thank you, Jim.
It's like
being lost in a place you know really
well, you can't get your bearings.
Sometimes it comes back to you
and sometimes...
I'm sorry, Owen.
What've you got to be sorry for?
I don't want to put you through this.
Last night, I dreamt that you left me.
Come on. Nobody's leaving anyone.
(KATIE SNIFFLING)
How is that possible?
We don't know.
I've never seen anything like it.
It's not the brain deteriorating,
it's a clear physical tumour.
-That wasn't there last week?
-Not that we saw.
-You were right to ask for another scan.
-So, what do we do now?
We have to view this as good news.
Katie, we need to take you into surgery
soon as possible and remove the tumour.
You understand?
Katie?
I can't remember your name.
You sure she's up to this?
We're going to do everything
we can for her.
-I'm sorry.
-Who the hell are you?
I tried to tell them
you should prepare for the worst.
No, you can't go in there.
Oh, my God.
Katie.
-What is it?
-I'm sorry, I tried to stop them.
She's dead.
That thing in her head
is an alien life form.
It incubates in the brain,
disrupting the shape and functions.
When it's attacked or threatened,
it emits a toxic gas
that's fatal to humans.
-It clears pretty quickly.
-She can't be dead. She can't be dead.
I'm calling the police.
Tell them that Torchwood's
already here and dealing with it.
That'll save them a call-out.
I need to take her brain back with me.
Don't touch her. Don't touch her.
-How are you feeling?
-Where is she?
-Where is who?
-Katie. Katie Russell.
She's a junior doctor. She works here
and we're about to get married.
-Let's get you back into bed.
-Get off me! Where is she?
(SHOUTING) Where is she? Where is she?
He was wearing a military uniform.
He has an American accent.
I promise, we have checked
all the security footage.
There was no such man.
Jim Garrett was poisoned
by some alien toxin.
Jim Garrett was in a car accident.
The American said that
he wanted her brain and there was...
There was an alien creature or...
This happened, okay?
This is not some trauma
or delayed grief
or whatever you're scribbling down.
Katie's tumour was inoperable.
There was nothing
anyone could have done.
This is just... This is wrong.
I'm giving you three months'
prescribed rest.
-Don't come into work.
-Yeah.
This isn't right. He was there.
It wasn't just me. He was there, too.
That is not what happened.
That's not what happened.
You !
You could have saved her!
You could have...
You could have saved her.
I couldn't. I really couldn't.
(OWEN CRYING)
OWEN : You're not a figment
of my imagination
and I don't know
what's happening any more.
Maybe this is
what a mental breakdown feels like.
JACK: You're fine.
It's the rest of the world
that's delusional.
Why her?
There is no reason.
Your life doesn't end with her.
What are you going to do now?
Go back to work?
See echoes of her in every corridor?
You need a purpose.
I'm building something.
-I need a medic.
-You want me?
You made them take more scans,
kept trying to track me down.
You don't give up easily.
I need someone like that
to work with me in Cardiff.
-To fight aliens?
-Exactly.
Look, I...
I don't know what happened to Katie.
And I don't know who you really are.
-But there is no such thing as aliens.
-You think?
I'm having a breakdown,
a mental collapse.
Owen.
Why did you become a doctor?
I thought if I could save one life,
mine would be worthwhile.
But you save one,
and there's another and another
clawing at you, demanding to be saved.
And even if you do succeed,
you can never save enough.
Maybe here you can.
-Heavens.
-H i.
Careful!
-If that falls...
-Okay, softly.
(BOTH SCREAM)
-Okay.
-Just be very careful.
Okay, all right. I'm gonna get you out.
This one. Okay.
-You have do it very, very gently.
-Okay.
There's no way
this is gonna drop on you.
Whoa !
-Quiet.
-Okay. Okay, silent.
I'm going to do this
as quickly as possible.
Listen to me,
I'm going to get you out of this.
Look at me. Trust me.
-Okay, Owen, hold my hand.
-Slowly.
Hold my hands.
JACK: You okay?
OWEN : Yeah.
You all right? Tosh, what happened?
TOSHIKO: Broken arm. Bruised ribs.
About an inch away
from being crushed by a girder.
OWEN : We were lucky.
IANTO: We all were.
-Jack, who's done this?
-I don't...
RHYS: Where's the SUV?
(BEEPING)
-Oh, no.
-Jack, what does he want?
Oh, déjà vu. Or did I say that already?
Hey, team!
Of course, there might be
a few less of you by now.
Don't know if you liked my little gift.
Of course, you can't die.
And with all that life, all that time,
you can't spare any for me. Oh!
Say hi to the family.
No way. It can't be.
Been a while since
you've seen your brother, eh, Jack?
Gray?
Okay, here is what's going to happen.
Everything you love,
everything you treasure, will die.
I'm going to tear your world apart,
Captain Jack Harkness.
Piece by piece. Starting now.
Maybe now you'll want
to spend some time with me.
This was a targeted attack.
He killed the four most senior officers.
If it gets out what happened here,
there'll be a city-wide panic.
Let's go get ourselves a good view.
What have you done?
We're going to put
this city back together.
We're going to find Jack.
And we're going to punish John.
He's completely crippled us, Gwen.
You're no fun.
Owen, get out of there.
What have you done with my brother?
This is going to get nasty.
What if this is how it all ends?